SAKSHAM ARORA

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

1400 Millersport Hwy Buffalo • Buffalo, NY 14221 • 716-939-5841 • saksham1011@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Experience in front-end website design and development, website maintenance and information security using several front-end technologies like HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap and JavaScript. Deep understanding of UI/UX design principles and working knowledge of responsive (mobile-first) web page design.

EDUCATION

State University of New York at Buffalo, Buffalo, NY

B.A., Computing and Applied Mathematics

December 2017

Relevant coursework: Data Structures in C++; Digital Systems; Discrete Mathematics; Introduction to Java; Numerical Analysis; Linear Algebra; Probability and Statistics; Partial Differential Equations

COMPUTER SKILLS

Operating Systems: Windows, Mac, Linux

• Programming Languages: Java, C++, Python, Shell

• Web Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery

• Frameworks: Bootstrap

• Databases: SQL, Microsoft Access

• Tools: Eclipse, Visual Studio, Xcode, Pixelmator Pro

WORK EXPERIENCE

Web Developer, Subboard, Inc., State University of New York at Buffalo, Buffalo, NY (Jan 2016 - Present)

- Conceptualized, planned, and executed original designs for a mobile responsive website www.subboard.com that helped provide information and services to new enrolled students
- Built user interface and designed overall user experience using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Bootstrap for www.subboard.com
- Managed and updated Microsoft Access Database for <u>offcampushousing.buffalo.edu</u> by performing frequent updates based on user requirements and troubleshot to resolve any issues
- Developed a WebView iOS app for Subboard website
- Developed a mobile app on iOS for <u>WRUB</u> (radio station for UB) to enable users to play music while the phone is locked

Network Administrator Assistant, State University of New York at Buffalo, Buffalo, NY (Jan 2016 - Present)

- Supported in assembling the web server for www.subboard.com
- Assisted in setting up Apache server on Ubuntu to install IT ticketing system
- Assisted in setting up two tier PKI hierarchy on windows server for pharmacy to ensure better security and HIPAA compliance
- Installed printers, computers, and other computer peripherals for various Subboard department personnel

Student Worker, Campus Dining, State University of New York at Buffalo, Buffalo, NY (Aug 2013 - Dec 2015)

- Performed routine duties in dining hall such as food preparation, plating and serving food, verifying meal plans, cleaning kitchen and dining facilities and stocking supplies
- Communicated and provided assistance to customers as needed

RELEVANT PROJECTS

- MaxHeap Implemented a vector-based MaxHeap data structure in C++
- Sorting-Stanford-SNAP-Files Wrote several functions in C++ to Sort/Traverse a file that stores
 edges of a graph in Stanford SNAP file format in C++

- Scrabble Game Implemented several functions and tests in Scrabble game for a team project in Java
- Matching Game Implemented a matching game with three different columns using swing components and event handling
- **Temperature Converter Application –** Built a temperature converting app on IPhone using swift programming
- Heat Variation Graphs Plotted several heat and wave equations graphs using Python in Partial Differential Equations

ACTIVITIES

- Participant, Hackathon (UBHacking), University at Buffalo, 2014
- Member, Indian Student Association, University at Buffalo, 2013 2017
- Member, High School Soccer team, 2012
- Member, High School Badminton team, 2011